Finding Aid of the American Academy of Allergy, Asthma & Immunology Records, 1923-2015
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
- Records, 1923-2015, UWM Manuscript Collection 139; 257.9 cubic ft. (741 boxes) 40 binders 1 oversize folder 30,895 digital files (79.5 GB) 1 film reel 4 safety film negatives
  - 12. Oral History Interviews of the Oral History Project for the AAAAI, 2000-2002, 44 audiocassettes
    - Seebohm, Paul M., 2000
      - Transcript (Box 511, Folder 24)
    - Sheffer, Albert, 2001
      - Interview, 2 audiocassettes (Box 541)
      - Transcript (Box 511, Folder 25)
    - Siegel, Sheldon, 2000
      - Interview, 1 audiocassette (Box 454)
      - Transcript (Box 511, Folder 26)
    - Slavin, Raymond G., 2001
      - Interview, 2 audiocassettes (Box 541)
      - Transcript (Box 511, Folder 27)
    - Talmage, David, 2000
      - Interview, 1 audiocassette (Box 454)
      - Transcript (Box 511, Folder 28)
    - Toogood, John, 2000
      - Interview, 1 audiocassette (Box 454)
      - Transcript (Box 511, Folder 29)
    - Wasserman, Stephen, 2002
      - Interview, 1 audiocassette (Box 541)
      - Transcript (Box 511, Folder 30)
    - Zweiman, Burton, 2001
      - Interview, 1 audiocassette (Box 541)
      - Transcript (Box 511, Folder 31)
  - 13. Historical Material, 1923-1985
    The series contains historical material, primarily from parent organizations of the AAAAI. Included are Sheldon Cohen's files for AAA's 25th Anniversary, which provides background for the AAAAI.
    - Advisory Board of American Allergists, Correspondence
      - 1936-1946 (Box 432, Folder 1)
      - 1947-1968 (Box 432, Folder 2)
    - Amalgamation Committee, American Academy of Allergy, American College of Allergists, Correspondence, Reports, 1943-1968 (Box 432, Folder 3)
    - American Academy of Allergy
      - Administration
        - Correspondence, 1961-1962, 1973 (Box 432, Folder 4)
        - Contract, Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 449, Folder 37)
        - Cost Evaluation, 1962 (Box 432, Folder 5)
        - James O. Kelley Contract, 1969 (Box 432, Folder 6)
      - Allergy Symposium, Program, 1945-1946 (Box 432, Folder 7)
      - Annual Meeting
        - 2nd, Schedule of Committee Meetings, 1945 (Box 432, Folder 8)
        - 3rd, Dinner Speech by Stearns Bullen, 1946 (Box 432, Folder 9)
      - Autonomous Board on Allergy Special Report, 1953 (Box 437, Folder 2)
      - Clinical Allergy Orientation, Flyers, 1945-1946 (Box 432, Folder 10)
      - Constitution Changes and Amendments, 1947 (Box 449, Folder 38)
      - Continuing Education, Programs, 1952, 1955 (Box 432, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 432, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence Regarding Merger, 1943-1944 (Box 432, Folder 13)
      - Incorporation Papers, 1948-1949, 1958 (Box 432, Folder 14)
      - Incorporation Papers, By-laws, Minutes of first meeting, 1949-1950 (Box 433, Folder 23)
      - Membership Material, undated (Box 432, Folder 15)
      - Report to the Committee to Evaluate the Activities of the American Academy of Allergy, 1958 (Box 432, Folder 16)
      - Presidential Addresses, 1933, 1942, 1945, 1951-1958, 1960, 1962, 1965, 1968-1976, 1978-1985 (Box 432, Folder 17)
    - American Allergic Society, Membership Solicitation, 1923 (Box 432, Folder 18)
    - American Association for the Study of Allergy
      - Annual Meeting
        - Dinner Dance Program, 1938 (Box 432, Folder 19)
        - Notice and Member Roster, 1941 (Box 437, Folder 6)
        - Programs, 1923-1942 (Box 433, Folder 1-3)
        - Transcript, 1932 (Box 433, Folder 4)
      - Business Meeting, Transcripts, 1931-1935, 1939 (Box 433, Folder 5)
      - Constitution and Membership Roster, 1940 (Box 433, Folder 6)
      - Executive Council and Business Meeting Minutes, 1923-1942 (Box 433, Folder 7-8)
      - Membership Roster, 1944 (Box 433, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1924, 1930, 1950, undated (Box 433, Folder 10)
    - American Board of Allergy
      - Correspondence and Documents Regarding Recognition by the American Board of Internal Medicine, 1946-1955 (Box 433, Folder 11)
      - Reports, Correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 433, Folder 12)
      - By-Laws, 1948 (Box 433, Folder 13)
    - American Board of Internal Medicine, Memorandum, 1936, undated (Box 433, Folder 14)
    - American College of Allergists, Constitution, Correspondence, 1966, 1968, undated (Box 433, Folder 15)
    - American College of Physicians
      - Bulletin of Postgraduate Courses, 1944-1945 (Box 433, Folder 16)
      - Coursework in Allergy, 1940-1941 (Box 433, Folder 17)
    - American Society for the Study of Allergy, Annual Meetings, Programs, 1940-1941 (Box 433, Folder 18)
    - Association of Allergy Clinics of Greater New York, Membership Roster, 1942 (Box 433, Folder 19)
    - Association for the Study of Allergy
      - Annual Meeting Program, 1933 (Box 433, Folder 21)
      - Constitution and Membership Roster, 1933 (Box 433, Folder 22)
      - Correspondence Regarding Annual Meeting, 1937-1943 (Box 434, Folder 1)
      - Financial Reports, 1941-1943, undated (Box 434, Folder 2)
    - Ballad of the Allergists and Addendum, from a American Academy of Allergy Scrapbook compiled by Karl Figley, 1944-1946 (Box 434, Folder 3)
    - Canadian Society for the Study of Allergy, Annual Meeting Program, 1948 (Box 434, Folder 4)
    - Chicago Society of Allergy, Program Announcements, 1932-1934 (Box 434, Folder 5)
    - Continuing Medical Education Information, 1941, undated (Box 437, Folder 5)
    - Cooke, Robert A., Bibliography, undated (Box 475, Folder 9)
    - Forum on Allergy, 1939-1945 (Box 434, Folder 6)
    - Fiftieth Anniversary Issue,Journal of Allergy and Clinical Immunology, Sheldon Cohen Files, 1979-1980 (Box 434, Folder 7)
    - George Piness Files, 1936-1950 (Box 434, Folder 8)
    - J. Harvey Black, Telegram Announcing Death, 1958 (Box 437, Folder 1)
    - Jewish Hospital of Brooklyn, Allergy Course for Physicians, 4th Semi-Annual Meeting Program, 1937-1938 (Box 434, Folder 9)
    - Joint Committee on Standards, Correspondence, 1932-1939 (Box 434, Folder 10)
    - Merger of the Society for the Study of Asthma and the American Association for the Study of Allergy, Correspondence, Reports, 1943-1944 (Box 434, Folder 11)
    - Merger of the American Association for the Study of Allergy and the Society for the Study of Asthma, Miscellaneous Documents, 1943 (Box 434, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1932-1947, undated (Box 434, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Historical Material, Sheldon Cohen Files, 1968 (Box 434, Folder 14)
    - New England and Regional Allergy Proceedings,Firsts in Allergy, I-IV, 1984-1985 (Box 495, Folder 5)
    - Newsclippings Regarding Allergy and Asthma, 1948-1949, undated (Box 434, Folder 15)
    - Pathology of Allergic Diseases, by Milton Bohrod, 1947
      - Slides, Lantern slides (Box 496)
        Request the assistance of an archivist to view the lantern slides.
      - Syllabus (Box 449, Folder 39)
    - Photograph Identifications, undated (Box 434, Folder 16)
    - Society for the Study of Asthma and Allied Conditions
      - Annual Meeting
        - Papers Presented, 1940 (Box 434, Folder 17)
        - Programs, 1925-1943 (Box 434, Folder 18-20)
      - Fall Meeting, Announcements and Programs, 1925, 1930-1936, 1938, 1940-1943 (Box 435, Folder 1)
      - Business Meeting Minutes, 1941 (Box 437, Folder 4)
      - Constitution and By-Laws, 1924, 1932 (Box 435, Folder 2)
      - Membership and Program Files, 1923-1943 (Box 435, Folder 3-7)
      - Secretary-Treasurer's Report, 1941 (Box 437, Folder 3)
      - Program Abstracts, Announcements, Correspondence, 1936-1940 (Box 435, Folder 8)
    - Southeastern Allergy Association, Annual Meeting, Program, 1948 (Box 435, Folder 9)
    - Southwest Allergy Forum, 1945-1946, 1948 (Box 435, Folder 10)
    - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary of American Academy of Allergy & Immunology (AAAI), Historian's Review, Sheldon Cohen Files
      - April 1966-July 1968 (Box 435, Folder 11-13)
      - August 1968-1969, undated (Box 436, Folder 1-6)
    - Visual Education in Allergy Hay Fever Producing Plants of the State of California with Particular Reference to Southern California, 1948 (Box 436, Folder 7)
  - 14. Artifacts from the History of Asthma Treatment, before 1950
    Series includes late nineteenth- and early twentieth-century asthma remedies, e.g., asthmatic cigarettes and asthma powders.
    - Abbott Allergenic Extract, Mixed Ragweed Pollen, before 1950, Cardboard box (Box 442)
    - Blosser's Cigarettes, before 1920, Cardboard box (Box 442)
    - Brater's Powder, before 1920, Tin canister (Box 442)
    - Brewer and Company, Epinephrine Hydrochloride, before 1950, Cardboard box (Box 442)
    - Dr. Guild's Green Mountain Asthmatic Cigarettes, 1940s, Cardboard box (Box 442)
    - Dr. Guild's Green Mountain Asthmatic Compound, 1940s, Tin canister (Box 442)
    - Dr. J.D. Kellogg's Asthma Remedy, before 1910, Tin canister (Box 442)
    - Dr. J.D. Kellogg's Relief for Spasms or Paroxysms of Asthma, before 1910, Tin canister (Box 442)
    - Dr. Kinsman's Asthma Remedy, before 1950, Tin canister (Box 442)
    - Kutnow's Anti-Asthmatic Powder, before 1920, Tin canister (Box 442)
    - Lilly Hypodermic Tablets (Placebo), before 1950, Glass bottle (Box 442)
    - Peak Flow Meter, undated, Tube (Box 441)
    - People's Asthma Powder, before 1950, Tin canister (Box 442)
    - Zoagriaine Respirant, before 1950, Cardboard box (Box 442)
  - 15. Memorabilia, 1960, 1993, 2001-2008, undated
    Series contains more contemporary items, including awards and paperweights.
    - Bronze Anvil Award, Presented by the Public Relations Society of America, 2001 (Box 719)
    - Paperweight, AAA&I, undated (Box 719)
    - Paperweight, In Appreciation for Support of Education and Research Programs, 1993 (Box 719)
    - Pins, Miscellaneous, 1993, undated (Box 719)
    - Prism Award, Public Relations Society of America, 2004 (Box 719)
    - Robert A. Cooke Medallion, undated (Box 719)
    - Robert A. Cooke Medallion, New Copy, 2008 (Box 719)
    - Stress-reliever Nose, National Allergy Bureau, undated (Box 719)
- Additions, 1988-2010, Accession 2011-011; 2 cubic ft. (2 boxes); Additions of files pertaining to drug studies, dating 1988 to 1991.
- Publications and Annual Meeting Materials, 1997-2013, Accession 2013-038; 3 cubic ft. (3 boxes); Additions of publications and annual meeting materials, dating from 1997 to 2013.
- Publications and Other Additions, 1995-2015, Accession 2015-035; 1 cubic ft. (1 box); Accession largely consists of publications as well as meeting materials, brochures, and photographs, dating from 1995 to 2015.